George Sigletos

DevOps Engineer - Textkernel - Semantic Recruitment Technology

Amsterdam - Email mij via Indeed: indeed.com/r/George-Sigletos/2a6421afdf79bc28

Working as a devops engineer at Textkernel, supporting Jobfeed, a vertical search engine for job openings. I hold a PhD in Computer Science and I am mainly interested in data mining. I have hands-on experience with both software development and operations, NoSQL databases (Cassandra, Mongodb), programming languages (Ruby, Perl, Python, Java), relational databases (Mysql) and fulltext search engines (sphinx, solr). I am very fond of doing backend development using Ruby and Cassandra and recently I started to show interest in Apache Spark.

WERKERVARING

DevOps Engineer

Textkernel - Semantic Recruitment Technology - Amsterdam - januari 2014 tot heden

I am part of the IT operations team and the main responsible for the operational needs of Jobfeed that include monitoring, scheduling, deployment and scaling. Jobfeed is a vertical search engine for job openings that has been expanded to seven countries so far. I am also the primary database administrator for MySQL, Cassandra, Mongodb that the company is using, while I am also doing technical consultancy and implementation of several customer projects.

Web mining engineer

Textkernel - Semantic Recruitment Technology - april 2007 tot december 2013

I was part of an agile team that was doing software development and maintenance for Jobfeed. Primarily programming in Perl, my main role was to maintain, improve and scale the backend. Among many different things, I did also contribute in improving, using machine learning, the filtering of potential vacancies and the extraction of relevant information from their content. I also led the team's effort to improve the content deduplication of vacancies, again using machine learning and participated in the implementation of several customer projects

Research Associate

National Centre of Scientific Research "Demokritos" - januari 2000 tot augustus 2005

PhD research. I also participated in the several research projects, including the following: • Crossmarc: A cross-lingual multi-agent retail comparison engine. My main involvement was to build and maintain the information extraction system that was used to process Web pages describing laptop products. I have also developed an annotation tool in JAVA for users to annotate relevant information within the Web pages and used later on to train an information extraction system • Mitos: Document filtering, information extraction, data mining applied to the domain of financial news. My main involvement was to develop and maintain a name-matching module for organizations extracted from financial news

Part-time developer

Computer Technology Institute - juli 1997 tot juni 1998

Java development for European projects

OPLEIDING

PhD in Computer Science

Ethnikon kai Kapodistriakon Panepistimion Athinon - A $\theta \acute{\eta} \nu \alpha$ 2000 tot 2005

Diploma in Computer Engineering and Informatics

University of Patras - Πάτρα 1994 tot 1999

VAARDIGHEDEN

Scripting languages (Ruby, Perl, Python), Data mining / Web mining, Backend development, Databases (MySQL, Cassandra, MongoDB), Web services